exportgenius.in 2018-11-16

# Privacy Policy | Export Genius | Export Import | Custom duty

Export Genius Privacy Policy explains who we are, how we collect and use personal information about You and how you can exercise your privacy rights. Export Genius respects your preferences concerning the collection and use of your personal information. Your privacy and trust are important to us and the following policies and statements explain how Export Genius and its subsidiaries and affiliates handle your personal information. So, read our Privacy Policy thoroughly and for any concerns, _contact us_.

## What does Export Genius do?

Export Genius is a leading market research agency, providing import-export global trade data of 60+ countries and analytical business intelligence reports of 20+ countries and all Harmonized System (HS) classified commodities. We undertake all possible measures to maintain updated and effective Privacy Policy and standards to protect personal information of users that they share on this Website. Export Genius may amend or change or modify any of the terms listed in Privacy Policy as and when need arises and without any prior notice. So, You are requested to go through this Privacy Policy in detail before using this Website.

#### What personal information does Export Genius collect and why?

We ask you to provide personal information, such as your contact details, user credentials and employment information.

Types of Personal Information | Why We Collect It  
---|---  
Company information | To verify authenticity of you and your business.  
Contact details including email address, phone number(s), postal address, etc. | To respond to correspondence and enquiries you send us. In some cases, to collect information required to provide products and services requested by you. Also, to obtain your feedback regarding our products and services.   
Financial information including bank account details, credit card details, etc. | To process payment for your data order and subscription plan.  
User credentials including name, email address and other personal information. | To set up and maintain your user account.   
Information, which you share via chat, comment, enquiry form and news boards. | To reach you for knowing your data requirements.  
Non-personal and autonomous identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser details, operating system type, date & time of website access, etc. | To monitor our website in improving website performance and managing promotional activities.  
  
## How does Export Genius keep my personal information secure?

We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect Your personal information that we collect through our Website. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security in a suitable way and to the risk of processing your personal information.

## International Data Transfers

###### Your personal information including company name, e-mail address, phone numbers, postal address, bank details and other required information; may be transferred to and processed in countries other than country in which you reside. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country. We have taken appropriate measures to make sure that your personal information shared on this Website will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Personal information, which You provide through this Website is disclosed to our sales representatives only for the purpose of managing your accounts and processing your data orders. We don’t sell your general or financial privacy to any other third party for any promotional purpose. However, we may use your personal details like phone numbers, email address, etc. for sending newsletters and other business offers. Export Genius may also share your personal information to our business partners and agents for other lawful purposes. 

## Your Data Protection Rights

##### Your data protection rights include the right to access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information. You also have the right to withdraw the consent you have provided to us. You have the following data protection rights:

  * You can access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information provided through our Website.
  * You can object to processing of your personal information and ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information.
  * You can opt-out of marketing communications at any time from our Website and Blog as well. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in the marketing e-mails that we send you on your email address.
  * If we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. 

_Please email any questions or doubts about the Export Genius Privacy Policy to[info@exportgenius.in](mailto:info@exportgenius.in)._
